Guide to the North Carolina State University, Athletics, Media Relations Records
North Carolina State University, Athletics, Media Relations Records
- Women's Track and Field, 1979-1985; 1979 1985; Women's Track and Field was established as a varsity sport in or before 1979. In 1979, Julie Shea won the AIAW national title for the 5,000 meters; in 1980, she also won the 3,000 5,000 and 10,000 meters national titles. In 1981, Shea won the 5,000 meters AIAW national title. In 1983, Betty Springs won the 5,000 and 10,000 meters NCAA championship, and was ranked number one in the United States and third in the world for the 5,000 meters by the Track and Field News. Women's Track and Field team member Joan Benoit won a gold medal at the 1984 Los Angeles Summer Olympics. In 1985, the NC State 4x100 meter team won the NCAA championship, and in 1991, Laurie Gomez won the 5,000 meters NCAA championship. Tyrell Taitt won the triple jump championship in 1993, and Kristin Price won the 10,000 meters national title in 2002.
  This series contains records from the Women's Track and Field teams, including clippings, media guides, meet information, questionnaires, statistics, press releases, rosters, schedules, brochures, and other publications and general information. Materials are arranged chronologically by season.
  - Brochure, 1979-1980 (Box 261, Folder 4)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1979-1980 (Box 250, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, 1980-1981 (Box 261, Folder 8)
  - Brochure, 1981-1982 (Box 261, Folder 9)
  - General information, 1981-1982 (Box 252, Folder 1)
  - Operating budget, 1981-1982 (Box 261, Folder 11)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1981 (Box 252, Folder 3)
  - NCAIAW State Championship Meet, 3-4 Apr. 1981 (Box 261, Folder 28)
  - Brochure, 1982-1983 (Box 261, Folder 13)
  - General information, 1982-1983 (Box 252, Folder 9)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1982 (Box 252, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Coast Relays (10th Annual), 27 Mar. 1982 (Box 252, Folder 12)
  - The Athletics Congress (TAC) Championships, 9 May 1982 (Box 252, Folder 14)
  - Itineraries, 1983 (Box 252, Folder 17)
  - Atlantic Coast Relays, 26 Mar. 1983 (Box 252, Folder 19)
  - Great Raleigh Relays, 9 Apr. 1983 (Box 252, Folder 20)
  - Wolfpack Qualifier, 18 May 1983 (Box 252, Folder 21)
  - Brochure, 1984-1985 (Box 261, Folder 14)
- Women's Fencing, 1979-1983; 1979 1983; Women's Fencing was established as a varsity sport in or before 1979, and retained varsity status through at least the 1983 season.
  This series contains records from the Women's Fencing teams, including media guides and general information. Materials are arranged chronologically by season.
  - General information, 1979-1983 (Box 220, Folder 25)
  - Media guide, 1980 (Box 261, Folder 29)
  - Media guide, 1981-1982 (Box 261, Folder 30)
- Women's Golf, 1981-1986; 1981 1986; In 1984, Women's Golf became a recognized sport by the Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC), with four teams competing (Duke, UNC-Chapel Hill, NC State, and Wake Forest), but was discontinued by the ACC in 1986. Although Women's Golf returned to the other three schools in 1992, NC State did not re-establish a team again until 2001. Page Marsh became the head coach when the team was reinstated, and led them to seven straight appearences in the NCAA Tournament (2001-2007). Although the team did not make it to the NCAA Tournament in 2008, Lauren Doughtie became the first individual golfer at NC State to make it to the NCAA Tournament.
  This series contains records from the Women's Golf teams, including clippings, media guides, meet information, questionnaires, statistics, press releases, rosters, schedules, brochures, and other publications and general information. Materials are arranged chronologically by season.
  - Lady Wolfpack Golf Invitational tournaments, 1981-1982 (Box 261, Folder 31)
  - General information, 1981-1983 (Box 261, Folder 32)
  - Questionnaires, 1981-1985 (Box 262, Folder 1)
  - Media guide, 1982-1983 (Box 262, Folder 2)
  - Media guide, 1983-1984 (Box 262, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1984-1986 (Box 262, Folder 4)
  - Meets and results, 1984-1986 (Box 262, Folder 5)
  - Brochure, 1985 (Box 262, Folder 6)
  - Brochure, 1986 (Box 262, Folder 7)
- Volleyball, 1976-2000; 1976 2000; Volleyball was established as a varsity sport at NC State in 1976, with Kay Yow serving as coach during the first seasons. Volleyball remained a varsity sport as of 2009.
  This series contains records from the Volleyball teams, including clippings, media guides, game information, statistics, press releases, rosters, schedules, brochures, and other publications and general information. Materials are arranged chronologically by season.
  - Prospectus, 1976 (Box 262, Folder 8)
  - Slides, photographic negatives, 1976 (Box 262, Folder 9)
  - Media guide, 1978 (Box 262, Folder 10)
  - Media guide, 1980 (Box 262, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, 1981 (Box 262, Folder 12)
  - Volleyball Camp, 1981 (Box 262, Folder 13)
  - Brochure, 1982 (Box 262, Folder 14)
  - Volleyball Camp, 1982 (Box 262, Folder 15)
  - Brochure, 1984 (Box 262, Folder 16)
  - Wolfpack Volleyball Camp, 1991 (Box 262, Folder 17)
  - Wolfpack Volleyball Camp, 1993 (Box 262, Folder 18)
  - Schedule, 1995 (Box 262, Folder 19)
  - Schedule, 1988 (Box 277, Folder 7)
  - Media guide, 1997 (Box 262, Folder 20)
  - Media guide, 2000 (Box 262, Folder 21)
- Cheerleading, 1981; 1981 1981
  - Cathy Buckey Cheerleading Camps, 27-31 Jul. 1981 (Box 266, Folder 35)
- Cross Country, 1988 (Box 277, Folder 8)
  - General Information, 1988 (Box 277, Folder 8)
- Men's Track and Field, 1903-1994; 1903 1994; In 1898, the first Men's Track team was organized for intercollegiate competition; however, it was disbanded after the season and track did not reappear at NC State until 1905. In 1923, Men's Track and Field was granted varsity status. The team won championships in the Southern Conference for the first time in 1951, and the Atlantic Coast Conference in its innaugural year of 1953.
  This series contains records from the Men's Track and Field teams, including clippings, media guides, event information, statistics, press releases, rosters, schedules, player questionnaires, brochures, and other publications and general information. Materials are arranged chronologically by season.
  - Records and results, 1903-1920 (Box 242, Folder 15)
  - Southern Conference Indoor Games (14th Annual), 26 Feb. 1949 (Box 242, Folder 16)
  - Southern Conference Indoor Games (15th Annual), 25 Feb. 1950 (Box 242, Folder 17)
  - Southern Conference Outdoor Track Championship Meet (27th Annual), 18-19 May 1951 (Box 242, Folder 18)
  - NC State vs. South Carolina, 1952 (Box 244, Folder 1)
  - Southern Conference Indoor Games (17th Annual), 1 Mar. 1952 (Box 244, Folder 2)
  - Southern Conference Indoor Games, Freshman Division (17th Annual), 1 Mar. 1952 (Box 244, Folder 3)
  - Carolina Relays, College Division, 5 Apr. 1952 (Box 244, Folder 4)
  - NC State vs. UNC-Chapel Hill, 22 Apr. 1952 (Box 244, Folder 5)
  - NC State vs. Duke, 7 May 1952 (Box 244, Folder 6)
  - NC State vs. Davidson, 10 May 1952 (Box 244, Folder 7)
  - Southern Conference Outdoor Track Meet (28th Annual), 16-17 May 1952 (Box 244, Folder 8)
  - General information, 1956 (Box 244, Folder 9)
  - General information, 1957 (Box 244, Folder 10)
  - General Information, 1989 (Box 277, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Games (4th Annual), 23 Feb. 1957 (Box 244, Folder 11)
  - Men's Track and Field press releases, 1958 (Box 244, Folder 12)
  - General information, 1959 (Box 244, Folder 13)
  - General information, 1960 (Box 244, Folder 14)
  - General information (Box 244, Folder 15)
  - Carolinas' AAU Track Meet, 20 May 1961 (Box 244, Folder 16)
  - General information, 1962 (Box 244, Folder 17)
  - Carolinas' AAU Track Meet, 1962 (Box 244, Folder 18)
  - General information, 1963 (Box 244, Folder 19)
  - Carolina State-Record Relays (1st Annual), 6 Apr. 1963 (Box 245, Folder 1)
  - Carolinas' AAU Track Meet, 18 May 1963 (Box 245, Folder 2)
  - General information, 1964 (Box 245, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 1964 (Box 245, Folder 4)
  - Carolina State-Records Relays (2nd Annual), 4 Apr. 1964 (Box 245, Folder 5)
  - Carolinas' AAU Track Meet, 16 May 1964 (Box 245, Folder 6)
  - General information, 1965 (Box 245, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Games (12th Annual), 27 Feb. 1965 (Box 245, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track Meet (12th Annual), 14-15 May 1965 (Box 245, Folder 9)
  - General information, 1966 (Box 245, Folder 10)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 1966 (Box 245, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track Meet (13th Annual), 13-14 May 1966 (Box 245, Folder 12)
  - General information, 1967 (Box 245, Folder 13)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 1967 (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - WTVD Track and Field Championships of North Carolina (2nd Annual), 5-6 May 1967 (Box 246, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track and Field Championships (14th Annual), 12-13 May 1967 (Box 246, Folder 3)
  - General information, 1968 (Box 246, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 1968 (Box 246, Folder 5)
  - General information, 1969 (Box 246, Folder 6)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 1969 (Box 246, Folder 7)
  - WTVD-11 Track and Field Championships of North Carolina (4th Annual), 2-3 May 1969 (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - Meets and results, 1970 (Box 246, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Meet, 28 Feb. 1970 (Box 246, Folder 10)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track and Field Championships, 8-9 May 1970 (Box 246, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 246, Folder 12)
  - General information, 1971 (Box 246, Folder 13)
  - Meets and results, 1971 (Box 246, Folder 14)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Indoor Track Championships, 1971 (Box 246, Folder 15)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track and Field Championships (18th Annual), 14-15 May 1971 (Box 246, Folder 16)
  - Brochure, 1972 (Box 246, Folder 17)
  - General information, 1972 (Legalbox 243, Folder 2)
  - Indoor Track, 1972 (Box 246, Folder 18)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (19th Annual), 12-13 May 1972 (Box 246, Folder 19)
  - Brochure, 1973 (Box 246, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Legalbox 243, Folder 3)
  - General information, 1973 (Box 246, Folder 21)
  - Indoor Track, 1973 (Box 246, Folder 22)
  - Meets and results, 1973 (Box 246, Folder 23)
  - Questionnaires, 1973 (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - Southeastern U.S. Masters Track and Field Championships (3rd Annual), 7-8 Apr. 1973 (Box 247, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (20th Annual), 27-28 Apr. 1973 (Box 247, Folder 3)
  - NCAA Track and Field Championships (52nd Annual), 5-9 Jun. 1973 (Box 247, Folder 4)
  - Brochure, 1974 (Box 247, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 247, Folder 6)
  - General information, 1974 (Box 247, Folder 7)
  - Indoor Track, 1974 (Box 247, Folder 8)
  - Meets and results, 1974 (Box 247, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (21st Annual), 13-14 May 1974 (Box 247, Folder 10)
  - NCHSAA Track and Field Championships(70th Annual), 24 May 1974 (Box 247, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 13)
  - General information, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 14)
  - Indoor Track, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 15)
  - Meets and results, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 16)
  - Questionnaires, 1975 (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - Southeastern U.S. Masters Track and Field Championships (5th Annual), 4-6 Apr. 1975 (Box 249, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (22nd Annual), 19 Apr. 1975 (Box 249, Folder 3)
  - Brochure, 1976 (Box 249, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - General information, 1976 (Box 249, Folder 6)
  - Indoor Track, 1976 (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Meets and results, 1976 (Box 249, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (23rd Annual), 16-17 Apr. 1976 (Box 249, Folder 9)
  - NCHSAA Track and Field Championships (71st Annual), 28 May 1976 (Box 249, Folder 10)
  - Brochure, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 12)
  - General information, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 13)
  - Indoor Track, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 14)
  - Meets and results, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 15)
  - Questionnaires, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 16)
  - Brochure, 1978 (Box 249, Folder 17)
  - General information, 1978 (Box 249, Folder 18)
  - Indoor Track, 1978 (Box 249, Folder 19)
  - Meets and results, 1978 (Box 250, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaires, 1978-1981 (Legalbox 243, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (25th Annual), 21-22 Apr. 1978 (Box 250, Folder 2)
  - Brochure, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 4)
  - Distance running camp, 1979-1981 (Box 250, Folder 5)
  - Events held at North Carolina State University, 1979-1980 (Box 250, Folder 6)
  - General information, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 7)
  - General information, 1979-1981 (Box 251, Folder 13)
  - Indoor Track, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 8)
  - Meets and results, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 9)
  - Questionnaires, 1979 (Box 250, Folder 10)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1979-1980 (Box 250, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, 1980 (Box 250, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Box 250, Folder 13)
  - Equipment orders, 1980-1983 (Box 250, Folder 14)
  - General information, 1980 (Box 251, Folder 1)
  - General information, 1980-1981 (Box 251, Folder 2)
  - Indoor Track, 1980 (Box 251, Folder 3)
  - Junior Striders Track and Field Club, 1980 (Box 251, Folder 4)
  - Meets and results, 1980 (Box 251, Folder 5)
  - Recruiting, 1980-1981 (Box 251, Folder 6)
  - Results, 1980-1981 (Box 251, Folder 7)
  - Questionnaires, 1980 (Box 251, Folder 8)
  - Wolfpack Track and Field Clinic, 13-14 Dec. 1980 (Box 251, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Track and Field Championships (27th Annual), 17-19 Apr.1980 (Box 251, Folder 10)
  - North Carolina State University Invitational Track and Field Meet, 3 May 1980 (Box 251, Folder 11)
  - NCAA Track and Field Championships (59th Annual), 3-7 Jun. 1980 (Box 251, Folder 12)
  - Brochure, 1981 (Box 251, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 251, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Jack Bacheler, 1981 (Box 251, Folder 16)
  - General information, 1981-1982 (Box 252, Folder 1)
  - Operating budget, 1981-1982 (Box 218, Folder 21)
  - Track candidate form, 1981 (Box 252, Folder 2)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1981 (Box 252, Folder 3)
  - Wolfpack Track and Field Clinic (2nd Annual), 11-12 Dec. 1981 (Box 252, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Relays, 28 Mar. 1981 (Box 252, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina State University Invitational Open Track and Field Meet, 3 May 1981 (Box 252, Folder 6)
  - NCAA Track and Field Qualifier All-Conference Meet, 10 May 1981 (Box 252, Folder 7)
  - Brochure, 1982 (Box 252, Folder 8)
  - General information, 1982-1983 (Box 252, Folder 9)
  - Results, 1982-1983 (Box 252, Folder 10)
  - Track meet itineraries, 1982 (Box 252, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Coast Relays (10th Annual), 27 Mar. 1982 (Box 252, Folder 12)
  - Great Raleigh Relays, 9-10 Apr. 1982 (Box 252, Folder 13)
  - The Athletics Congress (TAC) Championships, 9 May 1982 (Box 252, Folder 14)
  - Brochure, 1983 (Box 252, Folder 15)
  - General information, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 16)
  - Itineraries, 1983 (Box 252, Folder 17)
  - Track candidate form, 1983 (Box 252, Folder 18)
  - Atlantic Coast Relays, 26 Mar. 1983 (Box 252, Folder 19)
  - Great Raleigh Relays, 9 Apr. 1983 (Box 252, Folder 20)
  - Wolfpack Qualifier, 18 May 1983 (Box 252, Folder 21)
  - WRAL Atlantic Coast Relays, 31 Mar. 1984 (Box 253, Folder 1)
  - Brochure, 1985 (Box 253, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference Outdoor Track and Field Championship (41st Annual), 22-23 Apr. 1994 (Box 253, Folder 3)
  - Competative events in the Track program, undated (Box 253, Folder 4)